<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Global Glimpse</string>




    <string name="Rhodes">
        "The Colossus of Rhodes, also known as the Statue of Rhodes, was a gigantic bronze statue of the sun god Helios, erected on the Greek island of Rhodes around 280 BCE. It was one of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World, renowned for its colossal size and impressive craftsmanship.

The statue stood at the entrance of the harbor of Rhodes, welcoming ships and visitors to the island. It was constructed to commemorate the successful defense of Rhodes against a siege by the Macedonian king Demetrius Poliorcetes in 305 BCE. The Rhodians decided to repurpose the siege engines left behind by the defeated army to build the statue as a tribute to their patron deity, Helios.

Designed by the sculptor Chares of Lindos, the Colossus of Rhodes was estimated to stand around 30 meters (approximately 98 feet) tall, making it one of the tallest statues of the ancient world. It depicted Helios, the personification of the sun, standing nude with a crown of sun rays on his head and a torch held aloft in his hand, symbolizing enlightenment and guidance.

The statue was constructed using a framework of iron bars and bronze plates, with the exterior surface sculpted in detail to resemble the god Helios. According to historical accounts, the construction of the Colossus took approximately 12 years to complete, and it was a marvel of ancient engineering and artistic skill.

For centuries, the Colossus of Rhodes stood as a symbol of the prosperity, power, and cultural achievements of the city-state of Rhodes. It attracted travelers and admirers from across the Mediterranean, who marveled at its grandeur and significance. However, the statue's existence was relatively short-lived.

In 226 BCE, just 54 years after its completion, a powerful earthquake struck Rhodes, causing significant damage to the statue. The Colossus reportedly collapsed at the knees and lay in ruins for centuries. Despite efforts to repair it, including proposals to rebuild the statue in its original form, the shattered remains of the Colossus were eventually sold as scrap metal by Arab conquerors in the 7th century CE."

Although the Colossus of Rhodes no longer stands, its legacy lives on in the annals of history and in the imagination of people around the world. It remains a symbol of human creativity, resilience, and the enduring quest for greatness.
    </string>
</resources>